<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Other" icon="rankcorrelation.png"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
	<name>Rank Correlation</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Computes correlation coefficients for pairs of
		columns, based on the sorting
		of its values only.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Calculates for each pair of selected columns a correlation
				coefficient, i.e. a measure of the correlation of the two variables.
			</p>
			<p>
				All measures are based on the rank of the cells. Where the rank of a
				cell value refers to its position in a sorted list of all entries.
				All correlation can be calculated on any kind of DataColumn. However
				please note that we use the default ordering of the values. If there
				is no ordering defined in the column, a string representation will
				be used.
				The node uses fractional ranks for equal values.
				<a
					href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spearman%27s_rank_correlation_coefficient"> Spearman's rank correlation coefficient </a>
				is a statistical measure of the strength of a monotonic relationship
				between paired data. Where the monotonic relationship is
				characterised by a relationship between ordered sets that preserves
				the given order, i.e., either never increases or never decreases as
				its independent variable increases.
				The value of this measure ranges
				from -1 (strong negative correlation) to 1 (strong positive
				correlation). A perfect Spearman correlation of +1 or −1 occurs when
				each of the variables is a perfect monotone function of the other.
				For Spearman's rank correlation coefficient the p-value and degrees
				of freedom are computed. The p-value indicates the probability of an
				uncorrelated system producing a correlation at least
				as extreme, if the mean of the correlation is zero and it
				follows a t-distribution with <i>df</i> degrees of freedom.
				<br />
				<a
					href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodman_and_Kruskal%27s_gamma"> Goodman and Kruskal's gamma</a>
				as well as
				<a
					href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kendall_tau_rank_correlation_coefficient">Kendall's tau rank correlation coefficient</a>
				is used to measure the strength of association between two measured
				quantities. Both are based on the number of concordant and
				discordant pairs. Kendall's Tau A and Tau B coefficients can be
				considered as standardized forms of Gamma. The difference between
				Tau A and Tau B is that Tau A statistic does not consider tied
				values, while Tau B makes adjustments for them. By tied observations
				we consider two or more observations having the same value. Both
				Kruskal's gamma and Kendall's Tau A are mostly suitable for square
				tables, whereas Tau B is most appropriately used for rectangular
				tables. The coefficients must be in the range from −1 (100% negative
				association, or perfect inversion) to +1 (100% positive association,
				or perfect agreement). A value of zero indicates the absence of
				association.
				<br />
			</p>
			<p>
				Rows containing Missing Values will be ignored, not used for the
				calculations. For other behaviors please resolve them before.
			</p>
		</intro>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Correlation Type">
				Chose the type of correlation here. There are the
				Spearman Correlation, two types of Kendalls Tau and Goodman and
				Kruskal's Gamma.
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Manual Selection">
			<option name="Include">
				This list contains the names of those columns in
				the input table for which correlation values should be computed.
			</option>

			<option name="Exclude">
				This list contains the names of those columns in
				the input table to be left out of the computation.
			</option>

			<option name="Filter">
				Use one of these fields to filter either the
				Include or Exclude list for certain column names or name substrings.
			</option>

			<option name="Buttons">
				Use these buttons to move columns between the
				Include and Exclude list. Single-arrow buttons will move all
				selected columns. Double-arrow buttons will move all columns
				(filtering is taken into account).
			</option>

			<option name="Enforce Exclusion">
				Select this option to enforce the current
				exclusion list to stay the same even if the input table
				specification changes. If some of the excluded columns are not
				available anymore, a warning is displayed. (New columns will
				automatically be added to the inclusion list.)
			</option>

			<option name="Enforce Inclusion">
				Select this option to enforce the current
				inclusion list to stay the same even if the input table
				specification changes. If some of the included columns are not
				available anymore, a warning is displayed. (New columns will
				automatically be added to the exclusion list.)
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Wildcard/Regex Selection">
			<option name="">
				Type a search pattern which matches columns to
				move into the Include list. You can use either Wildcards ('?'
				matching any character, '*' matching a sequence of any characters)
				or Regex. You can specify whether your pattern should be case
				sensitive.
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Type Selection">
				Select the column types that you want to include.
				Column types that are currently not present are depicted in italic.
			</option>
			<option name="p-value">
				Select which p-value should be computed for Spearman's rank
				correlation coefficient.
				<ul>
					<li>
						"two-sided" corresponds to the probability of obtaining a
						correlation value that is at least as extreme as the observed
						correlation.
					</li>
					<li>
						"one-sided (right)" corresponds to the probability of obtaining a
						correlation value that shows even greater <b>positive</b> association.
					</li>
					<li>
						"one-sided (left)" corresponds to the probability of obtaining a
						correlation value that shows even greater <b>negative</b> association.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Numeric input data">
			Numeric input data to evaluate
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Correlation measure">
			Correlation variables, p-values and
			degrees of freedom.
		</outPort>
		<outPort name="Correlation Model" index="1">
			A model containing the
			correlation measures. This model is appropriate
			to be read by the
			Correlation Filter node.
		</outPort>
		<outPort name="Rank table" index="2">
			A table containing the fractional ranks
			of the columns. Where the rank
			corresponds to the values position in a
			sorted table.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view name="Correlation Matrix" index="0">
			Squared table view showing
			the pair-wise correlation values of all columns. The color range
			varies from dark red (strong negative correlation), over white (no
			correlation) to dark blue (strong positive correlation). If a
			correlation value for a pair of column is not available, the
			corresponding cell contains a missing value (shown as cross in the
			color view).
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>