<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./blandaltmanplot.png" type="Visualizer"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Bland-Altman Plot</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Creates a Bland-Altman plot (also known as Tukey mean-difference plot) used to analyze the agreement of two different measurement methods.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Creates a Bland-Altman plot (also known as Tukey mean-difference plot) used to analyze the agreement of two
			different measurement methods.
			<br /><br />
			The plot shows the relationship
			between the mean of two measurements and their difference. The bias
			of the first method is shown which states how much higher or lower the
			measurements on average are compared to the measurements of the
			second method. It also shows the limit of agreement which state how
			much of a difference can be expected when using one method instead of
			the other.
			<br />
			<br />
			More information can be found in the original publication
			<a href="https://dx.doi.org/10.2307%2F2987937">"Measurement in Medicine: The Analysis of Method Comparison Studies"</a>.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Measurement 1 column">
				Column containing the values of the first measurement method.
			</option>
			<option name="Measurement 2 column">
				Column containing the values of the second measurement method.
			</option>
			<option name="Scale data with logarithm">
				First scale the values with a logarithm (base 2) to compensate for
				proportional bias (difference of two values is higher for higher
				mean values).
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="View Controls">
			<option name="Enable panning">
				Enable panning on the plot. To start panning click and drag the mouse.
				Note if panning and drag zooming is enabled, panning can be achieved
				by holding the Ctrl key and dragging the mouse.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable mouse wheel zooming">
				Enable zooming on the plot using the mouse wheel.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable drag zooming">
				Enable zooming on the plot by dragging the mouse and drawing a zoom
				rectangle. Dragging from the top-left down will create a zoom
				rectangle, dragging from the bottom right up will reset the zoom to
				fit the extends of the plot. Note if panning and drag zooming is
				enabled, panning can be achieved by holding the Ctrl key and
				dragging the mouse.
			</option>
			<option name="Show zoom reset button">
				Renders a button to resize the plot to it's extends.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Image options">
			<option name="Width of image (in px)">
				The width of the generated SVG image.
			</option>
			<option name="Height of image (in px)">
				The height of the generated SVG image.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<interactiveView name="Bland-Altman Plot">
		Displays a Bland-Altman plot
		visualization of the selected to measurements.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Measurement data">Data table containing the two
			measurements.</inPort>
		<outPort name="Bland-Altman Plot" index="0">The Bland-Altman Plot.
		</outPort>
		<outPort name="Measurements" index="1">The two selected
			measurements together with the calculated mean (x in the plot) and
			difference (y in the plot).</outPort>
		<outPort name="Bias and limits of agreement" index="2">The bias
			(mean of the difference) and the limits of agreement (95% of the
			points are within the limits of agreement).</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>