<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./kaplanmeier.png" type="Visualizer"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Kaplan-Meier Estimator</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Calculates the Kaplan-Meier estimator for a given data set of study subjects and events at certain time stamps.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            The Kaplan-Meier estimator, also known as product limit estimator, is used to estimate the survival function from lifetime data.
            It is often used to measure the fraction of study subjects that are still alive after a certain amount of time after treatment.
            The curve obtained from the Kaplan-Meier estimator takes right-censoring data into account so that subjects withdrawing from 
            the study prematurely or finish the study without event occurrence can be dealt with accordingly.<br/>
            The data passed to this node is a table with one row for each study subject. For each subject the event that is studied either
            occurred, so that the event column contains a boolean True value, or the subject left the study (boolean False). Additionally
            to this information the time the event or censoring has taken place must be present.
            More information about the Kaplan-Meier estimator can be found on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaplan–Meier_estimator">Wikipedia</a>.
        </intro>
        <option name="Time column">The time at which the event occurred.</option>
        <option name="Event column">Whether the event occurred (boolean True) or censoring occurred (boolean False).</option>
        <option name="Group column">The (optional) group the subject belongs to.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <interactiveView name="Kaplan-Meier Plot">
        Displays a Kaplan-Meier plot visualization of the data.
    </interactiveView>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data">The data to calculate the Kaplan-Meier estimator for</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Image">The SVG image of the plot</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Statistics">The estimator calculated for each group and time step</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>