<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./data_explorer.png" type="Visualizer"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.12" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.12 http://knime.org/node/v2.12.xsd">
	<name>Data Explorer</name>

	<shortDescription>
        Data Explorer is a exploration tool that allows having an
        overview on the data and its properties. Exploring the interactive view the node 
        intends to brings the insights and the understanding of the data.
        
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			The node presents the information about the data to explore. It consists of three 
			tabs: statistical, nominal and preview. The statistical and nominal tabs sum up the information 
			on each column, and given the information a user can decide in the interactive view which
			columns to include in the further analysis or exclude.
			<p><b>Statistical tab</b> shows main statistical parameters of the numerical data, such as 
			minimum, maximum, mean, median (optional) standard deviation, variance, skewness, kurtosis,
			overall sum,  number of zero values, number of missing values, number of not an object values,
			and positive and negative infinity values. 
			For each column the node also calculates the histogram of value distribution.</p>
			<p><b>Nominal tab</b>provides an overview on the characteristics of the nominal values, providing 
			the number of missing values, unique values, and top N most frequent and infrequent values. 
			Additionally, each data column has a histogram that shows the frequencies of all values used in a
			data column.</p>
			<p><b>Data Preview tab</b>shows first several rows of the studying dataset and the values it
			contains.</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Show median"> 
			Enables calculation of median for the statistical tab. 
			</option>
			<option name="Title">
			Adds title to the interactive view.
			</option>
			<option name="Subtitle">
			Adds subtitle to the interactive view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable global number format">
			Enables same number representation for all double values in the table interactive view.
			</option>
			<option name="Decimal places">
			Specifies the number of decimal places for all values in the table interactive view.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Table">
			<option name="Enable pagination">
			Enables exploring the tables split into pages.
			</option>
			<option name="Initial page size">
			The number of rows per page.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable page size change control">
			Enables to change the number of rows per page in the interactive view.
			</option>
			<option name="Selectable page sizes">
			Provides options for different number of rows per page in the preview. Values need to be comma separated.
			</option>
			<option name="Add 'All' option to page sizes">
			Enables "All" option to show all rows at once.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of rows for data preview">
			Selects the number of rows for the Data Preview tab.
			</option>
			
			<option name="Enable selection">
			Enables selection of the data column to exclude them from the further analysis. 
			</option>
			
			<option name="Enable searching">
			Enables searching of the values in the data tables.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable sorting on columns">
			Enables column sorting.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable 'Clear Sorting' button">
			Enables "Clear Sorting" button to cancel all applied sorting in the table.
			</option>
			<option name="Max number of nominal values">
			Approximate maximum number of distinct nominal values in a column. If the actual value is higher than the entered in this field, 
			the interactive view will show an warning.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of most frequent/infrequent nominal values">
			Creates additional columns with the number of most frequent and infrequent values in a nominal column. If the selected number is 
			equal to the overall number of distinct values in a column, only one column with all values will be created. In all cases values 
			are represented in the decreasing order of frequency.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Data Explorer View">
		Displays three tabs for data exploration: Statistical tab with statistical moments of numerical columns, 
		Nominal tab with characteristics of nominal data, and Data Preview tab with the selected number of rows of original data. 
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table">
			Table from which to compute statistics.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered Table">
			A table with filtered out by user columns, chosen in the interactive view.
		</outPort>
		<!-- <outPort index="1" name="Statistics Table">
			Table with numeric values.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="2" name="Nominal Histogram Table">
			Table with all nominal value histograms.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="3" name="Occurrences Table">
			Table with all nominal values and
			their counts.
		</outPort> -->
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
